# ALEXANDER LAMBROW

**Software Developer** 

alexanderlambrow.com

in linkedin.com/in/alexander-lambrow/

github.com/alambrow

# **Projects**

## **VibeHunt**

| Codebase |

Finding the right place to go out in the evening has again become an issue. This app aggregates real-time data from the BestTime and Google Maps APIs to help users select the venues with the best vibe for an evening out and about in Nashville, TN.

Tech stack: CSS3, HTML5, ReactJS, JSON Server, Google Maps API, BestTime API

## Truncheons and Flagons

| Codebase | View Live |

A medieval drinking game gone digital. Built by a team of four, this app employs Vanilla JavaScript and JSON Server to guide users through three rounds of a mock beer pong tournament.

Tech stack: CSS3, HTML5, JavaScript, JSON Server

### GiffyGram

| Codebase |

A nutty take on a popular photo-sharing app. Built with two teammates using Vanilla JavaScript and JSON server.

Tech stack: CSS3, HTML5, JavaScript, JSON Server

#### **EDUCATION**

#### HARVARD UNIVERSITY

Ph.D. German Literature (2019)

**UC, BERKELEY** 

M.A. German Studies (2013)

#### **DARTMOUTH COLLEGE**

B.A. Comparative Literature (2010) magna cum laude, Phi Beta Kappa

### **ABOUT**

I am a humanities Ph.D. and former university lecturer who has transitioned into software development over the past year. Since joining Nashville Software School this spring, I have been thrilled to see that the skills I developed in my first career—self-teaching, fastidious research, careful editing, and clear communication—translate well into the world of computer science. I feel fortunate to have found another line of work that allows me to continue learning and solving problems.

#### TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

#### SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

#### Nashville Software School | April 2021—September 2021

Full-time coding bootcamp, with a focus on teaching full-stack development (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Python, SQL, Django) through self-guided, project-based work

- Work individually and on small teams to develop single-page web applications with full CRUD functionality
- Manage workflow through GitHub Projects
- Plan data structures and implement data servers in Python
- Worked with external APIs like Google Maps API and BestTime API
- Style webpages with CSS3 and React-Bootstrap

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### APPLICATION MENTOR

### Crimson Education | June 2019—present

Web-based university admissions consulting company specializing in assisting college-bound students improve their personal profiles and gain admission to highly selective B.A. programs

- Work on teams of three to advise students on winning admissions strategies
- Specialize in essay writing, leading each student through an intensive, six-month brainstorming, writing, and editing process
- Coordinate work with 12+ teams/students at any given time

# POSTDOCTORAL SCHOLAR / LECTURER Vanderbilt University | August 2019—December 2020

- Instructed five undergraduate-level courses in German language and cultural history in the College of Arts & Science
- Conducted independent research in intellectual history, resulting in two articles and a book (forthcoming):
  - Sample work: "The Seriousness of Play: Johann Huizinga and Carl Schmitt on Play and the Political," Games and Culture 2020 | <u>View Online</u> |
- Presented research at international conference (NeMLA 2020)
- Assisted in the development of future courses as member of Undergraduate Curriculum Planning Committee

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (CONT.)

# TEACHING FELLOW / LECTURER Harvard University | August 2015—August 2019

- Taught twelve undergraduate-level courses in German language and cultural history at Harvard College and Harvard Summer School, including multiple 20-hour/week intensive courses; won a teaching prize for every semester of instruction
- Conducted independent research in cultural and intellectual history, resulting in one highly cited article and a 50,000word dissertation:
  - "14 December 1930: Robert Musil Meets Carl Schmitt" German Quarterly 2017 | View Online |
  - "Theogony ab ovo: Carl Schmitt's Political Aesthetics" (Dissertation) | View Online |
- Presented research at ten major academic conferences (ACLA, GSA, NeMLA)
- Hosted local chapter of the working group BTWH (Berkeley-Tübingen-Wien-Harvard); planned and secured over \$10,000 in grant funding for 2016 annual conference held in Cambridge, MA; organized discussions and social events for attendees
- Bernhard Blume Award (2016—2017) for "excellence in study of Germanic languages and literatures"

#### **GRADUATE TEACHING ASSISTANT**

#### University of California, Berkeley | August 2012—May 2013

- Instructed two undergraduate-level courses in German language
- Planned and secured \$8,000 in grant funding for academic conference on "Laughter" in German film and literature, held on Berkeley campus in 2013; invited keynote speaker from external institution; organized discussions and social events for attendees

#### **Fulbright Fellow**

#### U.S. Department of State | August 2010—June 2011

- · Awarded fellowship to spend the year after college in Dresden, Germany, as a representative of the United States
- · Worked as English-language teaching assistant in binational German-Czech secondary school